<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lamb on Karl&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.notmet.net/tags/lamb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lamb on Karl&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 15:29:01 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.notmet.net/tags/lamb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Late Lamb</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/04/late-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 15:29:01 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/04/late-lamb/</guid>
      <description>I was ready for lamb at Easter, but we&amp;rsquo;re a couple days past that now. It really snuck up on me, so the lamb was still frozen day-of. Well, we&amp;rsquo;ll make it today. I&amp;rsquo;m using a recipe similar to last time (recipe here), because after writing that post I realized the smoked lamb was really fantastic. Maybe it just needed some time in the fridge, but it was really fantastic later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lambtastic</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/04/lambtastic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 11:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/04/lambtastic/</guid>
      <description>This is lamb weekend. Some folks call it Easter weekend. I&amp;rsquo;m doing two legs of lamb - right leg and left leg. Both are about 4.7 lbs, $5.99 per pound. Today, Saturday, I&amp;rsquo;m going to smoke one based on this recipe, and tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m going to Sous Vide one based on the same recipe I&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past. Sarah likes meat more well-done than I do, and with lamb I don&amp;rsquo;t mind that much, so my target is medium-well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sous Vide Lamb Leg</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/sous-vide-lamb-leg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 19:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/sous-vide-lamb-leg/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a couple cooking projects going on today. I&amp;rsquo;m planning to be home all day, so I&amp;rsquo;ve started up a lamb leg in the Sous Vide. It&amp;rsquo;s a 5 lbs New Zealand lamb leg from Costco, all tied up.
 1 Tbsp salt 2 Tbsp melted butter 1 Tbsp (actually, a bit more) fresh rosemary 1 tsp pepper (or so) 6 big cloves of garlic 14 Kalmata olives  I put all that in the food processor and went until the garlic and rosemary were minced.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>