<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sourdough on Karl&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.notmet.net/tags/sourdough/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sourdough on Karl&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.notmet.net/tags/sourdough/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough With the Wrong Ingredients</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/sourdough-with-the-wrong-ingredients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/sourdough-with-the-wrong-ingredients/</guid>
      <description>We were out of sourdough once again, so it was time to make some fresh! About halfway through I realized we didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough of the bread flour I needed. Instead of 375g, I put in the 200g we had, then about 75g whole wheat flour and 100g all purpose flour.
And how did it turn out? The dough rose as normal, baked as normal, and tastes almost normal. The result is maybe a little tougher than usual, and slightly darker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brisket!  Sourdough!</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/11/brisket-sourdough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 01:03:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/11/brisket-sourdough/</guid>
      <description>15.5 pound brisket, $3.78 per pound, Sam&amp;rsquo;s in Idaho Falls, 4 Tbsp salt, 4 Tbsp pepper, 2 Tbsp garlic powder. Gonna put them on at 225℉ to start.
1810, 9 Nov: brisket on the smoker.
1830: sourdough is fermenting.
2200: flat is at 160℉, point at 142℉.
0210, 10 Nov: flat is 166℉, point 164℉. Crutched it!
0730: flat is 186℉, point 187℉. Turned temperature up to 250℉.
0845: put the rest of the ingredients in the bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sir Sour</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/sir-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 02:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/sir-sour/</guid>
      <description>Time to make sourdough again! The starter has been going for a couple weeks, but during that time it never adopted the stinkiness I associated with the early starter stages last time. It does seem to grow after feeding, it produces some alcohol on top&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s probably doing it&amp;rsquo;s thing enough to make some bread, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to try that out.
I was trying to diagnose the difference between the starter this time and last, and the best I can come up with is that the whole wheat flour is pretty old this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jerky and Sourdough</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/jerky-and-sourdough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 21:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/jerky-and-sourdough/</guid>
      <description>2120: pre-ferment done, by weight, except 2 Tbsp starter (40g).
For the jerky marinade, I followed the original foodie recipe but skipped the brown sugar (we were out), and subbed coconut aminos for soy sauce, left out liquid smoke, used regular paprika, and added slightly more cayenne then called for. I sliced the 2.5 lbs of top round with the grain mostly.
9:50: meat is in marinade.
0815, next day: I added the remainder of an old packet of regular yeast to the sourdough, about 5g.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even More Sourdough</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/even-more-sourdough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 12:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/even-more-sourdough/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re gonna try even more starter this time. I want to fill the large bread pans.
2200, night before: made pre-ferment. Used about 4 Tbsp starter, which was 100 g. Used 210 g flour and 240 g water to make two loaves.
0830: all ingredients in.
1030: starting bulk rise.
Bulk Rise Done
1700: finished bulk rise, in the pans now.
Starting to Rise in the Pans
2300: forgot to bake it today, oops ☺️ In the fridge now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Sourdough</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/more-sourdough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 01:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/more-sourdough/</guid>
      <description>I eat lots of bread. I eat lots of smoked meat, too, but unfortunately we need to eat all the stuff in the freezer now. It&amp;rsquo;s no time to make more smoked meat. But sourdough? That&amp;rsquo;ll be eaten in a week.
This time I used 1.5 Tbsp starter instead of 1, hoping to get more rise in the dough for the same about of sit time.
0930: finished kneading. Last night I did the pre-ferment, and earlier this morning I mixed in the rest of the ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Part Trace</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/sourdough-part-trace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 13:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/sourdough-part-trace/</guid>
      <description>Time to make more sourdough! One week later, the last loaf is gone. It was great, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to do that again. Even though the dough was a bit too fluid for me, the result was great, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to measure with the weights again.
Evening, 17 May: did the pre-ferment.
All In
0810, 18 May: things are smelling great! I put the rest of the ingredients together and mixed them up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Bread</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/sourdough-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 01:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/sourdough-bread/</guid>
      <description>I made a couple loaves of bread a couple weeks ago, based on a recipe in this book Sarah asked for, Josie Baker Bread. It was good, but actually not as good as when Sarah makes bread out of the book. Mine was not mixed uniformly (the two types of flour were a little noticeable in the end product), and it was saltier than it should have been. When Sarah makes bread from these recipes, it comes out amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>