<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on Karl&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.notmet.net/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on Karl&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 12:37:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.notmet.net/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UK and Ireland 2017 Summary</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/uk-2017-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 12:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/uk-2017-summary/</guid>
      <description>Sarah and I did a big trip of the UK and Ireland in October 2017. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a series of blog posts about these, intended to be informative to the person planning a similar trip. The posts are listed in order, below.
 London Post 1 London Post 2 London to Glasgow Scotland! Skye! Dublin Trips in Ireland Leftovers and Conclusion  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK 2017 Odds and Ends</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/uk-2017-odds-and-ends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 12:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/uk-2017-odds-and-ends/</guid>
      <description>Sarah and I are in line to get on our Norwegian Air flight home. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to wrap these posts up.
Some things to mention.
There&amp;rsquo;s lots of free WiFi. Still, having data access over the air is amazing. Google Project Fi gave me data access everywhere for the same price I pay at home. Phone calls are a bit expensive, but who makes those? WiFi calling is normal and texts are free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cork and the Cliffs</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/cork-and-the-cliffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 12:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/cork-and-the-cliffs/</guid>
      <description>We took some side trips from Dublin - one to Cork/Blarney castle/Midleton, and one to the Cliffs of Moher with a few extra stops in there&amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to take the train from Dublin to Cork, be and from there you take the Cork bus to Blarney castle and Midleton (Jameson&amp;rsquo;s major distillery). The train leaves from Dublin Heuston station (pronounced like the Houston in Texas), and takes a couple hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubsteppin Dublin</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/dubsteppin-dublin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 11:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/dubsteppin-dublin/</guid>
      <description>Watch Yourself at Dublin Airport
  Land at Dublin airport, take a trip through passport control, buy a Leap card at the tourist desk inside, put €20 on it, step outside to the bus stop, hop on the Airlink 757 bus, get a tour of downtown from the top of a double decker bus, step off 30 minutes later in downtown Dublin.
The EU really has passport control figured out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portree, Isle of Skye, Scotland</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/portree-isle-of-skye-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 17:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/portree-isle-of-skye-scotland/</guid>
      <description>I pushed the accelerator of the Peugeot 3008 to the floor, as I slammed it from fifth into third to accelerate up the hill and around the corner while the rock wall on the passenger side caused the proximity sensor to light and the lorry passed within inches on the driver&amp;rsquo;s side. Lock one, lock two, Loch Lomond on the right and an ancient wall on the left.
 Bathrooms at Loch Lomond</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving London and Going to Scotland</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/leaving-london-and-going-to-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 16:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/leaving-london-and-going-to-scotland/</guid>
      <description>On the morning of 7 Oct Sarah and I headed to the Stansted airport to fly to Glasgow. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly easy to get to the airport, there&amp;rsquo;s a train out of the Liverpool Street station that takes you right there. I got tickets in advance, and they&amp;rsquo;ll take them right from your phone screen. We cashed in the remaining funds on our Oyster cards before heading out - the normal Oyster machines at the station will give your remaining money back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeing London Sights and Saving Some Pounds</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/seeing-london-sights-and-saving-some-pounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 22:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/seeing-london-sights-and-saving-some-pounds/</guid>
      <description>Sarah on the Tower Bridge&amp;rsquo;s Glass Floor
  One thing I questioned before we got here was the wisdom of using this thing called The London Pass. It&amp;rsquo;s a card you purchase for 1, 2, or 3 days of entry into a ton of attractions. On our first partial day here I realized it was probably a good deal for us, in part just so that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to constantly wonder if any one place&amp;rsquo;s entry price was really worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foggy London Town Day 2 3/4</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/foggy-london-town-day-2-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 17:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/foggy-london-town-day-2-34/</guid>
      <description>Jolly old England!
Time for a bloggie postie! A bloggie-do! A postarama bloggy style!
 Sarah Waiting for Dinner
  Cheerio pip pip and wotnot ole chap!
 Tower Bridge Illuminated
  Ok, enough of that shit. Sarah and I are in London, England!
     Our Airbnb location in London  This is the end of our second full day here, and I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to say we didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep in too much.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
