<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pork Butt on Karl&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.notmet.net/tags/pork-butt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pork Butt on Karl&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.notmet.net/tags/pork-butt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Idaho Pork Butt</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/idaho-pork-butt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/idaho-pork-butt/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve smoked a couple things here in Idaho, and learned that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter where you&amp;rsquo;re making the meat, as long as you have a good starting point. Costco, in MD, and Sam&amp;rsquo;s Club here, have both provided excellent canvases on which to add smoke. Here in Idaho, though, I haven&amp;rsquo;t done pulled pork yet. Sam&amp;rsquo;s had a 10.8 lbs&amp;rsquo;er, $1.98 per pound.
Well, it&amp;rsquo;s time. We&amp;rsquo;ve got a baby coming any day now, and it&amp;rsquo;ll be nice to have a ton of extra meat in the freezer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork Butt for Friends</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/04/pork-butt-for-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 01:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/04/pork-butt-for-friends/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve got some of Sarah&amp;rsquo;s best friends in town, and some of their family is coming over Sunday, so I&amp;rsquo;m busting out the smoker to feed everybody. Time for some pulled pork!
2030, Friday: salted the 15 lbs butt with 2.5 Tbsp salt. It&amp;rsquo;s in the fridge now until Saturday night, when I&amp;rsquo;ll put 1 cup rub on and start it smoking at 225℉.
2215, Saturday: put the butt on the smoker at 225℉, after putting the rub on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork Butt Baby Shower</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/pork-butt-baby-shower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/pork-butt-baby-shower/</guid>
      <description>Alright! Time to BBQ for some other people. We&amp;rsquo;re throwing a baby shower for some friends of ours, and one of the I&amp;rsquo;m going to bust out the pork butt recipe I used last time, and do it the same.
I got a 15 lbs butt from Costco again - it looks beautiful. There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of dry rub from last time leftover in the cabinet.
24 Feb 2018, 1420: Began trimming the pork (took out chunks, left layers of fat about 1/8&amp;rdquo; thick - leaving a little more fat than last time), and then salting it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Smoking - Pork Butts and Salmon</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/01/third-smoking-pork-butts-and-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 14:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/01/third-smoking-pork-butts-and-salmon/</guid>
      <description>I began prep on Sunday night with 16 lbs of pork butt split into three parts, and 5.5 pounds of salmon. I used the typical salmon recipe, this time I did one quart of brine and still separated things into 4 bags. I used this pulled pork recipe, and this dry rub recipe per Ben&amp;rsquo;s recommendation. The pulled pork recipe looked to be a reasonable beginner&amp;rsquo;s complexity, too&amp;hellip; I considered this pork butt set to be just three of the one used in the recipe, so I had 1 cup of dry rub that I used on the three.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>