<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Karl&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.notmet.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Karl&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 14:21:18 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.notmet.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to My Own Cloud</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/05/switching-to-my-own-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 14:21:18 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/05/switching-to-my-own-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2020/05/google-play-music-dies-this-year-yt-music-library-imports-begin-today/&#34;&gt;Google Music is disappearing&lt;/a&gt; - it&amp;rsquo;s time to find a new way to host music in the cloud.  Google wants folks to move to YouTube Music as their music locker, but I&amp;rsquo;m tired of being jerked around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get away from Google Music I needed the following capabilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud-based method of storing music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser-based method for listening to that music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android app for listening to music, with method for downloading some music to device storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.notmet.net/2020/05/switching-to-my-own-cloud/next.gif&#34;
         alt=&#34;Judge Judy saying &amp;#39;next&amp;#39;, with a confused look on her face.&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nextcloud.com/&#34;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt; hosted on Dreamhost with Dreamobjects is the solution I chose.  This post will talk about how I settled on this, and how I made it work well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Teaching Intro to Programming</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/05/reflections-on-teaching-intro-to-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 14:11:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/05/reflections-on-teaching-intro-to-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last semester I had the pleasure of teaching programming as an adjunct professor at a local major university.  I sought out this opportunity because I genuinely enjoy teaching, I knew I&amp;rsquo;d have a little extra time on my hands, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s valuable to my current assignment to be in the community putting a face to the Air Force.  I cold-called the computer science department and asked around just prior to the fall semester, and they were interested in bringing me on for the spring semester.  More than that - they wanted someone to turn their existing Intro to Programming (in Python) course into an Internet-based course.  Python is my jam, so this sounded good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.notmet.net/2020/05/reflections-on-teaching-intro-to-programming/1024px-Python_image.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Python code on a computer screen, from https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Python_image.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Python lookin sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot while teaching this class: about teaching, about students, about learning Python, and about learning programming in-general.  I wanted to put my thoughts down because they&amp;rsquo;ve been bubbling around in my head.  I think this would be a great talk topic for some nerd conference too, so it makes sense to take the notes while they&amp;rsquo;re fresh.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfa AC1200 WiFi in Debian</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/05/alfa-ac1200-wifi-in-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 16:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/05/alfa-ac1200-wifi-in-debian/</guid>
      <description>I recently built a new desktop computer, and wanted a WiFi adapter that worked well for all kinds of Linux-y things&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not normally able to plug the desktop in over Ethernet, so WiFi is a simple choice. After my first purchase on Amazon got delayed and screwed up, I went with the USB Alfa Network AC1200 - full model number AWUS036ACH. This is reviewed pretty well, and folks say the drivers are capable of all kinds of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late Lamb</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/04/late-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 15:29:01 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/04/late-lamb/</guid>
      <description>I was ready for lamb at Easter, but we&amp;rsquo;re a couple days past that now. It really snuck up on me, so the lamb was still frozen day-of. Well, we&amp;rsquo;ll make it today. I&amp;rsquo;m using a recipe similar to last time (recipe here), because after writing that post I realized the smoked lamb was really fantastic. Maybe it just needed some time in the fridge, but it was really fantastic later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Leads to Grieving</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/04/change-leads-to-grieving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 12:48:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/04/change-leads-to-grieving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m listening to a webinar Air University is putting on called &amp;ldquo;Managing Traumatic Transitions&amp;rdquo; with Dr. Allen.  She is actually talking about managing any type of transition, because all kinds of transition are traumatic to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many of us consider how individuals will grieve when we introduce change?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s clear that some people do better with change than other people.  Any type of change.  But grieving?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.notmet.net/2020/04/change-leads-to-grieving/grieving_man.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A man in a business suit clearly disappointed about something.  Source: https://images.theconversation.com/files/172723/original/file-20170607-11305-yeecef.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Other sources agree, &amp;lsquo;change at work can trigger loss and grief&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-File Tools</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/03/one-file-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 15:20:15 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/03/one-file-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of us use computers that are locked-down by some corporate policy.  The restrictions prevent you from downloading software, or running anything that&amp;rsquo;s not pre-approved.  Most of us have used workarounds of some type - Excel spreadsheets created by that one guy in the office, Word documents with macros, Sharepoint sites, maybe even the occasional Powershell script&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-File Tools are open-source self-contained one-file utilities implemented as a webpage.  These are easily shared, easily used, their saved versions may contain your user data.  They don&amp;rsquo;t require an Internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarantine Brisket</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/03/quarantine-brisket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 12:33:04 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/03/quarantine-brisket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well - the world is on lockdown - it&amp;rsquo;s COVID-19 time.  We don&amp;rsquo;t have any toilet paper at the store, but there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of meat.  Don&amp;rsquo;t ask me why there&amp;rsquo;s such a disparity - I guess folks are stocking up on other things&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.notmet.net/2020/03/quarantine-brisket/IMG_20200323_084828.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;The shelves at Broulim&amp;#39;s - a few bags of all purpose flour remain, and a ton of large 25 lb bags remain on the bottom shelf.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Not much left&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden in Public</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/hidden-in-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 12:54:30 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/hidden-in-public/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/hidden-in-public/string-cheese.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A string cheese in plastic, sitting on a pillar in a breezeway&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The cheese stands alone&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How long can this string cheese sit here at the hospital entryway?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scope: Not Just Mouthwash</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/scope-not-just-mouthwash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/scope-not-just-mouthwash/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m teaching a Python class which acts as an introduction to programming, for most of the students there. This is an awesome experience - for me personally because I enjoy this, and for my resume. I hope to do this full-time someday, but today I&amp;rsquo;ve just got 3 sections of the same class.
We&amp;rsquo;re doing a lot of cool things that I should write about some other time - one of them is using a free, open source textbook called, Runestone - How to Think Like a Computer Scientist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idaho Pork Butt</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/idaho-pork-butt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/idaho-pork-butt/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve smoked a couple things here in Idaho, and learned that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter where you&amp;rsquo;re making the meat, as long as you have a good starting point. Costco, in MD, and Sam&amp;rsquo;s Club here, have both provided excellent canvases on which to add smoke. Here in Idaho, though, I haven&amp;rsquo;t done pulled pork yet. Sam&amp;rsquo;s had a 10.8 lbs&amp;rsquo;er, $1.98 per pound.
Well, it&amp;rsquo;s time. We&amp;rsquo;ve got a baby coming any day now, and it&amp;rsquo;ll be nice to have a ton of extra meat in the freezer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Github to Dreamhost</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/deploying-github-to-dreamhost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/deploying-github-to-dreamhost/</guid>
      <description>One feature I lost moving from Wordpress to Hugo for this blog was the ability to write a blog post from anywhere. I really liked being able to do that&amp;hellip; I could be riding in the car, or smoking brisket at 2 AM, or on vacation without a computer, and just login and write something.
I wanted that back - a posting solution from my cellphone.
The reason I lost that ability is because the simplest update process for Hugo is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Do No Limiting</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/first-do-no-limiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/first-do-no-limiting/</guid>
      <description>I recently saw a quote from an old boss of mine. The full paragraph is below, placing it in context, but the part that seems notable (pointed out by a friend of mine) is the, &amp;ldquo;it is important for a leader to &amp;hellip; not limit the potential of those they serve.&amp;rdquo;
 The command sets the tone/culture – which is difficult to quantify. I believe the best culture allows decision capability to those “closest to the fight,” while still maintaining a sense of responsibility should a problem arise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Advantage</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/comparative-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/comparative-advantage/</guid>
      <description>This morning I finished Planet Money&amp;rsquo;s Episode 963: 13,000 Economists. 1 Question.. These fine folks make one of my favorite podcasts - each week is a different look at something weird from a weird perspective. It sounds like it&amp;rsquo;s very market/economy focused, but it&amp;rsquo;s really focused on everything economics. In the past decades economics has branched out to look at nearly every field of human endeavor with a mathematical eye. It&amp;rsquo;s not always very successful, but the economist perspective does make me look at things differently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A January Experiment: Intermittent Fasting</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/a-january-experiment-intermittent-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/a-january-experiment-intermittent-fasting/</guid>
      <description>A friend and coworker told me about intermittent fasting a few years ago. She was doing it as part of a weight loss competition at work&amp;hellip; She was one of those folks that says they want to lose weight, but - I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure why they actually need to? My wife does that too - doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to lose weight but makes plans to do-so anyway.
Anyway - this woman was doing intermittent fasting by not eating for most of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive Pages</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/archive-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/archive-pages/</guid>
      <description>I recently converted this blog over from a WordPress installation to use static pages generated by Hugo. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Hugo for my other recent web creations and I&amp;rsquo;ve been very impressed. The templating system is very nice, the page generation is lightning fast, and I&amp;rsquo;m always able to find something near what I need in the themes.
One WordPress feature I liked was the listing of articles by year and month&amp;hellip; My blog had a little timeline on the side with each year and month listed, annotated with the number of postings I made during each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax Errors</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/syntax-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:15:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/syntax-errors/</guid>
      <description>Syntax Errors in Python are great. Here&amp;rsquo;s one:
 File &amp;quot;asdf.py&amp;quot;, line 2 print(&amp;quot;Result is: {}&amp;quot;.format(result)) ^ SyntaxError: invalid syntax result = ((5 * 10) + 15 print(&amp;#34;Result is: {}&amp;#34;.format(result)) Two lines of code&amp;hellip; Syntax error on the print line, evidently. But where? That line looks so simple and correct! And pointing directly at the t?
Well - it&amp;rsquo;s not really on the print line. Folks who have done any amount of programming will look at the preceeding line fairly quickly and notice the missing parenthesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough With the Wrong Ingredients</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/sourdough-with-the-wrong-ingredients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/sourdough-with-the-wrong-ingredients/</guid>
      <description>We were out of sourdough once again, so it was time to make some fresh! About halfway through I realized we didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough of the bread flour I needed. Instead of 375g, I put in the 200g we had, then about 75g whole wheat flour and 100g all purpose flour.
And how did it turn out? The dough rose as normal, baked as normal, and tastes almost normal. The result is maybe a little tougher than usual, and slightly darker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on SWAP</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/thoughts-on-swap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/thoughts-on-swap/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading the SWAP study. The thrilling congressionally-mandated &amp;ldquo;Software Acquisition and Practices&amp;rdquo; study conducted by the Defense Innovation Board. 292 pages of discussion about the US government&amp;rsquo;s software acquisition practices.
It&amp;rsquo;s actually quite a bit funnier than you&amp;rsquo;d expect. Admittedly, it helps to be in on the jokes.
These are the same folks that brought us: Detecting Agile BS. A document which is unexpectedly funny, for a government report, and accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Providing Cloud Services in the Air Force</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/providing-cloud-services-in-the-air-force/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 19:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/providing-cloud-services-in-the-air-force/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking this morning about how I might manage an Air Force unit that provides networked server management services. For some reason. I realized that, while I know a bit about some of the technology used to provide cloud services, and manage a server farm - or at least what’s used by some cloud providers - I don’t know much about how they organize their business. I started to wonder if someone from Rackspace, or AWS, or DigitalOcean had written a book about their management practices, or company organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smokin a Turkey</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/12/smokin-a-turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 15:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/12/smokin-a-turkey/</guid>
      <description>Alright! It&amp;rsquo;s Christmas! I meant to do this a week ago, but the turkey was still frozen, so we&amp;rsquo;re doing it today. If it turns out terrible we&amp;rsquo;ll be eating Chinese for dinner.
I got a pre-brined 12 lbs turkey for less than $1 per pound, put olive oil on the skin, then sprinkled on the rub I use on pork butt because it&amp;rsquo;s similar to what this person recommends anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brisket!  Sourdough!</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/11/brisket-sourdough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 01:03:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/11/brisket-sourdough/</guid>
      <description>15.5 pound brisket, $3.78 per pound, Sam&amp;rsquo;s in Idaho Falls, 4 Tbsp salt, 4 Tbsp pepper, 2 Tbsp garlic powder. Gonna put them on at 225℉ to start.
1810, 9 Nov: brisket on the smoker.
1830: sourdough is fermenting.
2200: flat is at 160℉, point at 142℉.
0210, 10 Nov: flat is 166℉, point 164℉. Crutched it!
0730: flat is 186℉, point 187℉. Turned temperature up to 250℉.
0845: put the rest of the ingredients in the bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CybatiWorks PI - Running on QEMU</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/11/cybatiworks-pi-running-on-qemu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 20:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/11/cybatiworks-pi-running-on-qemu/</guid>
      <description>CybatiWorks is an educational and research tool for learning about Industrial Control System cyber components. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it much, but it looks like it&amp;rsquo;ll simulate a PLC controlling a process, and it&amp;rsquo;ll do it on a Raspberry PI, GPIO-connected hardware, and a controlling HMI (Human-Machine Interface) desktop. You can buy the hardware pre-setup, then use it in a course.
The person who runs the company is Matthew Luallen, and he&amp;rsquo;s quite responsive over email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Use in Software Code Signing &amp; Malware C2</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/blockchain-use-in-software-code-signing-malware-c2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 16:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/blockchain-use-in-software-code-signing-malware-c2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve done some small research about blockchain recently, and just want to put my thoughts down on paperblog so I can stop thinking them. Most of this is rehashing information I’ve read, but the “signed code verification” piece towards the end is an idea of mine that I’ve not read about elsewhere.
 Blockchain is a hot term these days. It&amp;rsquo;s a popular management buzzword, and as such it can get thrown about as a cure for just about all that ails you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sir Sour</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/sir-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 02:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/sir-sour/</guid>
      <description>Time to make sourdough again! The starter has been going for a couple weeks, but during that time it never adopted the stinkiness I associated with the early starter stages last time. It does seem to grow after feeding, it produces some alcohol on top&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s probably doing it&amp;rsquo;s thing enough to make some bread, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to try that out.
I was trying to diagnose the difference between the starter this time and last, and the best I can come up with is that the whole wheat flour is pretty old this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking Salmon in Idaho</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/smoking-salmon-in-idaho/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/smoking-salmon-in-idaho/</guid>
      <description>Well, we&amp;rsquo;re still unpacking things, but we&amp;rsquo;ve been here for a bit. One of the things I was most excited to have arrive is the smoker - not gonna lie, that was a top priority. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to having some smoked Salmon again, and Sarah has mentioned it a couple times too.
There&amp;rsquo;s a Sam&amp;rsquo;s Club more convenient these days, so I picked up some salmon there. They had Sockeye for about $12 a pound, and &amp;ldquo;Atlantic&amp;rdquo; for about $9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitching Success - CO-STAR</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/pitching-success-co-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 16:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/pitching-success-co-star/</guid>
      <description>Idaho National Labs has a program right now called “CO-STAR”. Their researchers do great work, but as with any research group they are constantly advocating for funding, and researchers are constantly advocating among themselves for time.
Everybody spends time advocating for something. “Pitching” something. You want your boss to consider a smarter way of working, one that you’ve come up with? You pitch it to her. You want someone to use an open-source project you’ve created?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Differently</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/meet-differently/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 21:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/10/meet-differently/</guid>
      <description>A recent episode of the Freakonomics podcast covered meetings. Two or more people gathering to accomplish the business of business, as they defined it. It gave me some things I hope I remember the next time I’m organizing a recurring staff meeting…
 Organize an agenda around questions-to-answer Hold smaller meetings Keep track and time  Meetings need agendas, just about every book I’ve read which touches on meetings agrees on this point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consider How Well-Defined a Problem is When Building Teams</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/09/consider-how-well-defined-a-problem-is-when-building-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/09/consider-how-well-defined-a-problem-is-when-building-teams/</guid>
      <description>To improve innovation on a team, consider building a team differently based on the problem you’re facing. There are many ways of categorizing a problem your team must solve, but one is along the axis of well-definedness.
Well-defined problems – here, you know what you’re trying to solve, you know what end-state your audience will find acceptable, maybe you’ve seen similar problems solved elsewhere or you even know some current acceptable solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build on My Strengths and on My Peoples’ Strengths</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/build-on-my-peoples-strengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/build-on-my-peoples-strengths/</guid>
      <description>Everybody has a strength. Probably more than one. We are better-employed when we use our strengths. When possible, improving your weaknesses can make you a more effective individual… But we already possess our strengths and can put them to work now.
 Build on My Strengths and on My Peoples’ Strengths
   Know your peoples’ strengths and put those strengths to work. Build teams with a diversity of strengths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastermind Meetings</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/mastermind-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 23:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/mastermind-meetings/</guid>
      <description>When I was flight commander, supervising a group of fellow nerds with nerd jobs, I spent almost all of my time on the administrative requirements. They needed me to do the boss stuff - that was my official position!
I really wanted to do the nerd stuff though. It&amp;rsquo;s more fun, it&amp;rsquo;s my strength, and I&amp;rsquo;ve got more experience with it&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that as the boss I had input into many nerdy problems, and having that was rewarding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptions Sometimes Count and Facts May Not</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/perceptions-sometimes-count-and-facts-may-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 23:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/perceptions-sometimes-count-and-facts-may-not/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Perception is reality&amp;rdquo;
I&amp;rsquo;ve heard this quote numerous times. The falsehood evident in those words should be obvious, but these days perhaps it is not. Reality is reality, perception is perception.
Often reality and perception overlap heavily - but we don&amp;rsquo;t notice those times when our perceptions are correct. Our brains think that&amp;rsquo;s the default. There&amp;rsquo;s also almost always some amount of perception that doesn&amp;rsquo;t overlap reality - when our brain is jumping to conclusions and we are misled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Why</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/know-your-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 23:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/know-your-why/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m personally driven by a few ideas… Things I&amp;rsquo;m pretty passionate about. Improving cyber security in the US though education is a major one.
When I remember my goals they my action. Why do I want to volunteer to teach at a college? Why did I spend time building K-12 python, cyber security, and boolean logic short courses? Why do I look for opportunities to have my knowledgeable folks teach the rest of my folks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personality Inprocessing</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/personality-inprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 23:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/personality-inprocessing/</guid>
      <description>One of the things every leadership course includes is some discussion of personality types. Usually everyone has to take or retake a personality test for the Myers-Briggs system. You usually go around the room at some point and talk about, or show by example, the effects of each piece of the type.
Then, at some point, they recommend building teams with a diversity of personality.
But who actually ends up doing that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cyber Sim</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/the-cyber-sim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 22:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/the-cyber-sim/</guid>
      <description>This is a fictional imagining of what could be.
Dear Journal,
I took a refreshing break from my staff job today to keep up my &amp;ldquo;mission qualification&amp;rdquo;, and it really re-centered me. Sim time is something only pilots used to talk about, but the new &amp;ldquo;cyber sim&amp;rdquo; concept has brought that idea into the info ops world. Stupid name, great concept.
I took my laptop out to the local library and sat in a back room one of the squadrons borrows regularly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broken Windows</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/broken-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 13:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/broken-windows/</guid>
      <description>The broken windows theory of policing suggests that when police target small crimes like &amp;ldquo;vandalism, public drinking, and fare evasion,&amp;quot; and reduce visible signs of &amp;ldquo;crime, anti-social behavior, and civil disorder&amp;rdquo; they reduce the likelihood of further and worse crime.
This can certainly be taken too far, as in &amp;ldquo;stop-and-frisk&amp;rdquo; policies, if those are examples of broken windows policing, as some suggest.
When applied to a team you&amp;rsquo;re leading, broken windows policing looks like: making sure uniforms are still sharp and worn properly, office common spaces are kept tidy, individuals are shown respect in each interaction, promises are kept, report and presentation standards are being met, and people generally meet the requirements and standards of each of their duties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mission Qualified</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/mission-qualified/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 18:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/08/mission-qualified/</guid>
      <description>Commanders of operational units maintain their flying qualification. Most units in the Air Force aren&amp;rsquo;t flying units, but all have some mission they&amp;rsquo;re responsible for.
 Remain Qualified on your Mission System
   Once a quarter I should spend a day making sure I&amp;rsquo;m up to speed on the mission my folks are doing, and if possible I should get some practice actually doing it. At the least I should sit alongside folks as they execute the mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Broken Phone and Recovery</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/07/the-broken-phone-and-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 21:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/07/the-broken-phone-and-recovery/</guid>
      <description>A couple tips about getting an Android phone working again when you&amp;rsquo;re on the road are down below, along with tips about TOTP codes when your phone dies. I set those apart. But first, the background.
Recently, my Google Pixel stopped working for phone calls. That&amp;rsquo;s a big deal when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to move across the country. Not to mention the fact that failing to work for phone calls is an existential crisis for a cell phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I Hope I Remember - Be Deliberate</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/07/things-i-hope-i-remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 20:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/07/things-i-hope-i-remember/</guid>
      <description>Be deliberate.
   When the feeling in my organization is just a little&amp;hellip; off; when someone reacts to my words in a way that I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect; when someone doesn&amp;rsquo;t come through with that task they said they&amp;rsquo;d finish; when my organization isn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it by some metric; when I let someone down; when I get any negative feedback; when I need to give any negative feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jerky and Sourdough</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/jerky-and-sourdough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 21:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/jerky-and-sourdough/</guid>
      <description>2120: pre-ferment done, by weight, except 2 Tbsp starter (40g).
For the jerky marinade, I followed the original foodie recipe but skipped the brown sugar (we were out), and subbed coconut aminos for soy sauce, left out liquid smoke, used regular paprika, and added slightly more cayenne then called for. I sliced the 2.5 lbs of top round with the grain mostly.
9:50: meat is in marinade.
0815, next day: I added the remainder of an old packet of regular yeast to the sourdough, about 5g.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even More Sourdough</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/even-more-sourdough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 12:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/even-more-sourdough/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re gonna try even more starter this time. I want to fill the large bread pans.
2200, night before: made pre-ferment. Used about 4 Tbsp starter, which was 100 g. Used 210 g flour and 240 g water to make two loaves.
0830: all ingredients in.
1030: starting bulk rise.
Bulk Rise Done
1700: finished bulk rise, in the pans now.
Starting to Rise in the Pans
2300: forgot to bake it today, oops ☺️ In the fridge now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Sourdough</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/more-sourdough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 01:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/06/more-sourdough/</guid>
      <description>I eat lots of bread. I eat lots of smoked meat, too, but unfortunately we need to eat all the stuff in the freezer now. It&amp;rsquo;s no time to make more smoked meat. But sourdough? That&amp;rsquo;ll be eaten in a week.
This time I used 1.5 Tbsp starter instead of 1, hoping to get more rise in the dough for the same about of sit time.
0930: finished kneading. Last night I did the pre-ferment, and earlier this morning I mixed in the rest of the ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Fluency Assessment</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/computer-fluency-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/computer-fluency-assessment/</guid>
      <description>How do we assess an individual&amp;rsquo;s fluency with computers? We&amp;rsquo;re gonna go a little deeper than ability to use Microsoft Word&amp;hellip;
There&amp;rsquo;s a point, in knowledge and skill in the field of computer science, when programming languages mostly start to look and feel similar. &amp;ldquo;Learning a new language&amp;rdquo; is more like learning the peculiarities of a dialect of some language you already speak, than switching from English to Russian. When laypeople ask if you know a certain programming language, one which you do not already know, it occurs to you that answering in the negative would not be entirely correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Part Trace</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/sourdough-part-trace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 13:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/sourdough-part-trace/</guid>
      <description>Time to make more sourdough! One week later, the last loaf is gone. It was great, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to do that again. Even though the dough was a bit too fluid for me, the result was great, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to measure with the weights again.
Evening, 17 May: did the pre-ferment.
All In
0810, 18 May: things are smelling great! I put the rest of the ingredients together and mixed them up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Part Doughs</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/sourdough-part-doughs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 22:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/sourdough-part-doughs/</guid>
      <description>Gonna try to make it lighter this time by catching it at peak rise.
1900, 10 May: made pre-ferment. Measured by weight, which resulted in less ingredients by volume than he recommends.
0945, 11 May: added rest of flour and ingredients.
1145: finished stretching/folding.
1700: it still hasn&amp;rsquo;t risen as much as I&amp;rsquo;d hope for. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly risen, but it&amp;rsquo;s taking its time.
1900: the book recommends letting it increase by 50% by volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Bread</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/sourdough-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 01:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/05/sourdough-bread/</guid>
      <description>I made a couple loaves of bread a couple weeks ago, based on a recipe in this book Sarah asked for, Josie Baker Bread. It was good, but actually not as good as when Sarah makes bread out of the book. Mine was not mixed uniformly (the two types of flour were a little noticeable in the end product), and it was saltier than it should have been. When Sarah makes bread from these recipes, it comes out amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lambtastic</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/04/lambtastic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 11:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/04/lambtastic/</guid>
      <description>This is lamb weekend. Some folks call it Easter weekend. I&amp;rsquo;m doing two legs of lamb - right leg and left leg. Both are about 4.7 lbs, $5.99 per pound. Today, Saturday, I&amp;rsquo;m going to smoke one based on this recipe, and tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m going to Sous Vide one based on the same recipe I&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past. Sarah likes meat more well-done than I do, and with lamb I don&amp;rsquo;t mind that much, so my target is medium-well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork Butt for Friends</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/04/pork-butt-for-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 01:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/04/pork-butt-for-friends/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve got some of Sarah&amp;rsquo;s best friends in town, and some of their family is coming over Sunday, so I&amp;rsquo;m busting out the smoker to feed everybody. Time for some pulled pork!
2030, Friday: salted the 15 lbs butt with 2.5 Tbsp salt. It&amp;rsquo;s in the fridge now until Saturday night, when I&amp;rsquo;ll put 1 cup rub on and start it smoking at 225℉.
2215, Saturday: put the butt on the smoker at 225℉, after putting the rub on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoked Steaks</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/smoked-steaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 22:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/smoked-steaks/</guid>
      <description>One of my best buddies got us some steaks for our wedding, and now it&amp;rsquo;s time to smoke a couple of them! Four of the steaks are half pound fillet mignons, so I&amp;rsquo;m smoking two. I&amp;rsquo;m wrapping two slices of applewood bacon around each steak, putting 1/4 tsp salt on each, and smoking them at 225℉. I&amp;rsquo;ll use the thermometers, smoking them to 130℉, then searing top and bottom on cast iron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Jerky!</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/more-jerky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 20:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/more-jerky/</guid>
      <description>Alright, time for more beef jerky. This time I found top round roast for $3.99 per pound. I&amp;rsquo;m using the same recipe as last time, but it&amp;rsquo;s 3.5 lbs so I multiplied the marinade by about 1.5. I sliced the meat more along the grain than last time, and also slightly thicker.
1530: Meat is in the marinade.
1020 Sunday: Meat is on the smoker, 175℉, vents half open this time cause why not, that&amp;rsquo;s what I normally do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grilling a Whole Chicken</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/grilling-a-whole-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/grilling-a-whole-chicken/</guid>
      <description>We have a leftover chicken in the freezer, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to grill up a whole chicken again! We thawed it in the fridge over a couple days, then I marinated it in a bottle of Jerk sauce. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t found a great bottle of Jerk sauce - none are even approaching the right spiciness. Oh well. The chicken is medium sized, not as large as a roaster.
1910: Started butterflied chicken on the grill, cold side, skin up, legs towards the fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking Salmon</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/smoking-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 22:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/smoking-salmon/</guid>
      <description>Smoked salmon is one of my favorite foods. A luxury, truly. But, it&amp;rsquo;s much more reasonable when you can smoke it yourself. Salmon prices are at $8.99 a pound at Costco right now, which is a couple bucks more than I&amp;rsquo;m used to. Still worth it.
I&amp;rsquo;m using the same recipe I always use, with a bit over 5 lbs of salmon. This salmon was packed a couple days ago, unusually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Out Beef Jerky</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/trying-out-beef-jerky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/trying-out-beef-jerky/</guid>
      <description>My brother-in-law gave me a taste of some of his homemade beef jerky a couple weekends ago, and it was fantastic! Apparently it was also easy to make. Easy, delicious, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna try it! He used a dehydrator, but I plan to use a smoker to keep my wife&amp;rsquo;s dehydrator from getting strong flavors stuck in it.
https://www.foxvalleyfoodie.com/homemade-beef-jerky
Jason&amp;rsquo;s Recommended Starting Recipe
I got a 2.5 lbs bottom round steak, sliced it thin, then started it in the marinade below at 2130.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing About Writing Secure Shell Scripts</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/02/writing-about-writing-secure-shell-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 02:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/02/writing-about-writing-secure-shell-scripts/</guid>
      <description>I recently read this cautionary tale about shell scripts. https://www.linuxjournal.com/content/writing-secure-shell-scripts
It&amp;rsquo;s cautionary in two ways: it is intended to cause shell programmers caution, and I caution against you taking the article too seriously.
One of the biggest threats to the shell in memory was the Shellshock vulnerability. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t typically a direct threat to shell scripts, but one caused by a bug in a shell, and by other programs exposing parts of the shell to external input, often in unexpected and unlikely places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brisket and Salmon Again</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/12/brisket-and-salmon-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 01:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/12/brisket-and-salmon-again/</guid>
      <description>I ran out of brisket too quickly last time&amp;hellip; It makes a fantastic sandwich with Philly Cream Cheese (strangely enough). Then I eat a bunch of salmon on bagels, with Philly Cream Cheese&amp;hellip; The discovery that it&amp;rsquo;s the right cheese for both sandwiches has made shopping easier.
The brisket is 15.5 lbs, $2.99 per pound. Salmon is 6 lbs, didn&amp;rsquo;t get the price before tossing the package. We have to move in July and I hope I can keep up this hobby at the next stop in life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding Photos</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/11/wedding-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 14:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/11/wedding-photos/</guid>
      <description>If you were at our wedding, you already know that you looked awesome. But now you can see it in photos, too! Wedding photos are done, come see how great you looked!
https://sarahandkarl.sickendick.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brisket and Salmon!</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/09/brisket-and-salmon-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 22:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/09/brisket-and-salmon-2/</guid>
      <description>Just got married, just got honeymooned, just got back to work&amp;hellip; Time for some food!
17 lbs brisket, $61, 6 lbs salmon $9 per pound. Using the same recipe as usual.
2120: Brisket went on the smoker. 4.5 Tbsp salt, 4.5 Tbsp pepper, 2.25 Tbsp garlic powder.
2200: Fish is brining.
0530: Brisket at 165 and 166. Crutched it, and turned temperature up to 250. Also, moved fish to drying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brisket Numero Quatro</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/07/brisket-numero-quatro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 22:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/07/brisket-numero-quatro/</guid>
      <description>Well, there&amp;rsquo;s the possibility that the brisket I did last weekend won&amp;rsquo;t be enough meat&amp;hellip; And there&amp;rsquo;s the fact that I can get another one done in time&amp;hellip; So I&amp;rsquo;m making another brisket! We&amp;rsquo;ll just try for a repeat performance&amp;hellip;
14.1 lbs of brisket at $3.99 a pound&amp;hellip;
1045, 21 Jul: Brisket went on, fat cap up, 225℉. I should check the temperature after 8 hours, at 0645.
0900, 22 Jul: The flat passed 166℉ a couple hours ago, but the point was only at 162℉.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brisket Numero Tres</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/07/brisket-numero-tres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 16:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/07/brisket-numero-tres/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time to make the brisket for our Maryland wedding party! I&amp;rsquo;m pumped. Goals this time - turn up the temperature to 250℉ earlier, or put it in the oven for a long time. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go more than 24 hours, I can&amp;rsquo;t go for nearly that long&amp;hellip; Cut off less fat than last time. Keep the fat cap on top&amp;hellip;
The slab of meat I got was a full brisket, point and flat, 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Hitchcock</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/07/introducing-the-hitchcock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 03:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/07/introducing-the-hitchcock/</guid>
      <description>Some trucks have testicles, mine has a Hitchcock.
 The Hitchcock on the truck.
  Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be the outline of Alfred Hitchcock. It looks a lot like Harambe though&amp;hellip;

If you want to make one, check out the Thingiverse thing here. Download all files, open the zip up, and under &amp;ldquo;files&amp;rdquo; you&amp;rsquo;ll find an &amp;ldquo;stl&amp;rdquo; file. Hop on over to https://www.3dhubs.com/, click &amp;ldquo;start manufacturing&amp;rdquo;, and upload that &amp;ldquo;stl&amp;rdquo; file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidentiality and Integrity vs Availability</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/06/confidentiality-and-integrity-vs-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 15:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/06/confidentiality-and-integrity-vs-availability/</guid>
      <description>In computer security, there are three main axes for consideration - confidentiality, integrity, and availability (CIA). These are commonly thought of as things you desire out of a secure system. You want your communications to only be available to the intended agents, you want them to remain unchanged except when you intend them to change, and you want them to be available when you need them. Preferably, you want your communications to have all of those properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBQ Chicken</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/05/bbq-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 17:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/05/bbq-chicken/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been grilling for a while. Years. Have I ever taken it seriously? Yes - well, seriously enough to find that steak recipe I like&amp;hellip; Seriously enough to find that grilled whole chicken recipe I like&amp;hellip; Seriously enough to switch to a charcoal chimney&amp;hellip; All-in-all, maybe more serious than the casual griller, but not much more serious than that.
This memorial day, it&amp;rsquo;s time to BBQ a whole chicken. I mean - grill a chicken and use BBQ sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ribs and Salmon</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/05/ribs-and-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/05/ribs-and-salmon/</guid>
      <description>Time to try some ribs! I&amp;rsquo;ll use this recipe with the Memphis Dust dry rub I used on the pork butts. Also - we&amp;rsquo;re out of Salmon. I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a double batch of the usual. I&amp;rsquo;ll just do 6 pounds for four hours, then do 6 more for 4 more hours.

I bought what I thought were 3 racks of ribs - 3 large vacuum-packed things of ribs from Costco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drupal Exploited like Crazy</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/04/drupal-exploited-like-crazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 10:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/04/drupal-exploited-like-crazy/</guid>
      <description>It looks like https://github.com/nixawk/labs/issues/19 is being exploited like crazy right now. I was getting hits trying to exploit it every 4 hours or so, then the rate sped up for a time. Each hit was trying to download drupal.php from http://51.254.219.134.
Somebody has nulled out that file now, so infection rate will probably drop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Virus Total Catch</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/04/early-virus-total-catch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 10:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/04/early-virus-total-catch/</guid>
      <description>When you aren&amp;rsquo;t quite first into Virus Total, but not far off, and the malware author who hard-coded an IP address is still using that IP :-)
Virus Total says:
First Submission 2018-04-03 00:00:53
Last Submission 2018-04-03 22:07:38
Last Analysis 2018-04-03 22:07:38
Hopefully the IP address owner got a dozen emails already, they&amp;rsquo;re a cloud provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brisket and Salmon</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/03/brisket-and-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 02:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/03/brisket-and-salmon/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a Saturday and I don&amp;rsquo;t have a ton of stuff to do, and we&amp;rsquo;re out of Salmon! A terrible problem with one clear solution. It&amp;rsquo;s time to smoke more meat. We&amp;rsquo;ve eaten almost all of the chicken and pork now, so I can feel good doing another brisket.
Actually, I&amp;rsquo;ve been excited for the last two weeks to do another brisket. Ok, I&amp;rsquo;ve been excited since the last time I did one, but in the last two weeks the excitement has come to a head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork Butt Baby Shower</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/pork-butt-baby-shower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/pork-butt-baby-shower/</guid>
      <description>Alright! Time to BBQ for some other people. We&amp;rsquo;re throwing a baby shower for some friends of ours, and one of the I&amp;rsquo;m going to bust out the pork butt recipe I used last time, and do it the same.
I got a 15 lbs butt from Costco again - it looks beautiful. There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of dry rub from last time leftover in the cabinet.
24 Feb 2018, 1420: Began trimming the pork (took out chunks, left layers of fat about 1/8&amp;rdquo; thick - leaving a little more fat than last time), and then salting it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sous Vide Lamb Leg</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/sous-vide-lamb-leg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 19:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/sous-vide-lamb-leg/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a couple cooking projects going on today. I&amp;rsquo;m planning to be home all day, so I&amp;rsquo;ve started up a lamb leg in the Sous Vide. It&amp;rsquo;s a 5 lbs New Zealand lamb leg from Costco, all tied up.
 1 Tbsp salt 2 Tbsp melted butter 1 Tbsp (actually, a bit more) fresh rosemary 1 tsp pepper (or so) 6 big cloves of garlic 14 Kalmata olives  I put all that in the food processor and went until the garlic and rosemary were minced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smokin&#39; Chicken (and Salmon too)</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/smokin-chicken-and-salmon-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 21:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/smokin-chicken-and-salmon-too/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s today&amp;rsquo;s recipe! Based on a couple things:
 1. The recipe my mom sent me called Amway Grand Plaza Grilled Chicken Midwest - in my Google Docs Recipes folder 2. [https://ohsweetbasil.com/how-to-smoke-chicken/](https://ohsweetbasil.com/how-to-smoke-chicken/)  Other great info and ideas at these links - at some point I&amp;rsquo;d like to try the brine/minimal method:
 1. [http://www.smokegrillbbq.com/brine-smoked-chicken-recipe.html](http://www.smokegrillbbq.com/brine-smoked-chicken-recipe.html) 2. [https://www.traegergrills.com/recipes/poultry/whole-smoked-chicken](https://www.traegergrills.com/recipes/poultry/whole-smoked-chicken)  Anyway - here&amp;rsquo;s the plan today. Make a marinade of the ingredients below, divide this among four butterflied (spatchcocked?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sous Vide Burgers</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/sous-vide-burgers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 23:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/sous-vide-burgers/</guid>
      <description>* 1.5 Tbsp Worcester sauce per pound of meat * 2 Tbsp Duke&#39;s Mayo per pound of meat * .5 Tbsp minded garlic per pound of meat * 85% Ground Beef  Tonight we&amp;rsquo;re trying this recipe, and I made 8 7.5 oz burgers, starting from almost 3.5 lbs beef. I dropped all but two bagged burgers into the deep freeze, and dropped the other two in the indoors freezer, and then sous-vide&amp;rsquo;d those two at 130° for 1 hour, so they should come out on the rare side of medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Smoking - Pork Butts and Salmon</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/01/third-smoking-pork-butts-and-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 14:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/01/third-smoking-pork-butts-and-salmon/</guid>
      <description>I began prep on Sunday night with 16 lbs of pork butt split into three parts, and 5.5 pounds of salmon. I used the typical salmon recipe, this time I did one quart of brine and still separated things into 4 bags. I used this pulled pork recipe, and this dry rub recipe per Ben&amp;rsquo;s recommendation. The pulled pork recipe looked to be a reasonable beginner&amp;rsquo;s complexity, too&amp;hellip; I considered this pork butt set to be just three of the one used in the recipe, so I had 1 cup of dry rub that I used on the three.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Smoking - Brisket and Salmon</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/12/second-smoking-brisket-and-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/12/second-smoking-brisket-and-salmon/</guid>
      <description>Some notes from the second time I busted-out the smoker - I made brisket and salmon.
The brisket recipe is based on https://heygrillhey.com/recipe/texas-style-smoked-beef-brisket/, and the salmon recipe is the one I normally make.
I used a 16.5 lbs brisket from Costco, $2.99 per pound. Turned on the smoker to 225, added hickory wood chips. Trimmed 1-2 lbs fat off, took just over half an hour to trim. Sliced it in half so it would fit in the smoker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Smoking - Salmon</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/12/first-smoking-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/12/first-smoking-salmon/</guid>
      <description>Some notes from the first time I used the smoker - I made smoked salmon. The result was awesome - I&amp;rsquo;ve made it a couple times since then, and am just dropping this here for future note.
Recipe: https://honest-food.net/how-to-smoke-salmon-recipe/
I really just followed the instructions. I used Diamond Crystal Kosher salt, as he recommends - which, BTW, is probably going to become my goto salt. I used Costco salmon without the skin on - it worked perfectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK and Ireland 2017 Summary</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/uk-2017-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 12:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/uk-2017-summary/</guid>
      <description>Sarah and I did a big trip of the UK and Ireland in October 2017. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a series of blog posts about these, intended to be informative to the person planning a similar trip. The posts are listed in order, below.
 London Post 1 London Post 2 London to Glasgow Scotland! Skye! Dublin Trips in Ireland Leftovers and Conclusion  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK 2017 Odds and Ends</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/uk-2017-odds-and-ends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 12:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/uk-2017-odds-and-ends/</guid>
      <description>Sarah and I are in line to get on our Norwegian Air flight home. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to wrap these posts up.
Some things to mention.
There&amp;rsquo;s lots of free WiFi. Still, having data access over the air is amazing. Google Project Fi gave me data access everywhere for the same price I pay at home. Phone calls are a bit expensive, but who makes those? WiFi calling is normal and texts are free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cork and the Cliffs</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/cork-and-the-cliffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 12:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/cork-and-the-cliffs/</guid>
      <description>We took some side trips from Dublin - one to Cork/Blarney castle/Midleton, and one to the Cliffs of Moher with a few extra stops in there&amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to take the train from Dublin to Cork, be and from there you take the Cork bus to Blarney castle and Midleton (Jameson&amp;rsquo;s major distillery). The train leaves from Dublin Heuston station (pronounced like the Houston in Texas), and takes a couple hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubsteppin Dublin</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/dubsteppin-dublin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 11:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/dubsteppin-dublin/</guid>
      <description>Watch Yourself at Dublin Airport
  Land at Dublin airport, take a trip through passport control, buy a Leap card at the tourist desk inside, put €20 on it, step outside to the bus stop, hop on the Airlink 757 bus, get a tour of downtown from the top of a double decker bus, step off 30 minutes later in downtown Dublin.
The EU really has passport control figured out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portree, Isle of Skye, Scotland</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/portree-isle-of-skye-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 17:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/portree-isle-of-skye-scotland/</guid>
      <description>I pushed the accelerator of the Peugeot 3008 to the floor, as I slammed it from fifth into third to accelerate up the hill and around the corner while the rock wall on the passenger side caused the proximity sensor to light and the lorry passed within inches on the driver&amp;rsquo;s side. Lock one, lock two, Loch Lomond on the right and an ancient wall on the left.
 Bathrooms at Loch Lomond</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving London and Going to Scotland</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/leaving-london-and-going-to-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 16:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/leaving-london-and-going-to-scotland/</guid>
      <description>On the morning of 7 Oct Sarah and I headed to the Stansted airport to fly to Glasgow. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly easy to get to the airport, there&amp;rsquo;s a train out of the Liverpool Street station that takes you right there. I got tickets in advance, and they&amp;rsquo;ll take them right from your phone screen. We cashed in the remaining funds on our Oyster cards before heading out - the normal Oyster machines at the station will give your remaining money back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeing London Sights and Saving Some Pounds</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/seeing-london-sights-and-saving-some-pounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 22:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/seeing-london-sights-and-saving-some-pounds/</guid>
      <description>Sarah on the Tower Bridge&amp;rsquo;s Glass Floor
  One thing I questioned before we got here was the wisdom of using this thing called The London Pass. It&amp;rsquo;s a card you purchase for 1, 2, or 3 days of entry into a ton of attractions. On our first partial day here I realized it was probably a good deal for us, in part just so that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to constantly wonder if any one place&amp;rsquo;s entry price was really worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foggy London Town Day 2 3/4</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/foggy-london-town-day-2-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 17:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2017/10/foggy-london-town-day-2-34/</guid>
      <description>Jolly old England!
Time for a bloggie postie! A bloggie-do! A postarama bloggy style!
 Sarah Waiting for Dinner
  Cheerio pip pip and wotnot ole chap!
 Tower Bridge Illuminated
  Ok, enough of that shit. Sarah and I are in London, England!
     Our Airbnb location in London  This is the end of our second full day here, and I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to say we didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep in too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RasPi Flow Meter In A Pinch - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2016/08/raspi-flow-meter-in-a-pinch-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2016/08/raspi-flow-meter-in-a-pinch-part-2/</guid>
      <description>META: Part 1 describes the problem I&amp;rsquo;m trying to solve here.
I need a way to monitor water flow through my water filter over several days, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to sit and watch it.
So - I took a Raspberry Pi I&amp;rsquo;ve got and a little Python and hacked a solution together. The basic idea was that I&amp;rsquo;d position a plastic cup below the output stream of the waste water, I&amp;rsquo;d put two wires into the cup, I&amp;rsquo;d put a voltage on one wire and attempt to see the voltage on the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RasPi Flow Meter In A Pinch - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2016/08/raspi-flow-meter-in-a-pinch-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 23:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2016/08/raspi-flow-meter-in-a-pinch-part-1/</guid>
      <description>META: This first part is about the problem that caused me to build the solution. Part 2 is about the solution.
My new place has an awesome feature that was disabled when I moved in - a reverse osmosis water filter! It&amp;rsquo;s not a whole-house hookup, it&amp;rsquo;s just for the refrigerator and a dedicated tap on the sink. We definitely wanted to use this thing! At first, I just turned it on and it seemed to work fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Own OpenVPN</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2016/03/building-your-own-openvpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 20:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2016/03/building-your-own-openvpn/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to have a VPN setup for a while - I&amp;rsquo;ve never been entirely comfortable when using public wifi, even secured public wifi&amp;hellip; Open wifi? I feel a little crazy every time I connect. But I usually console myself that I&amp;rsquo;m not a target, I can make sure important connections are encrypted, and I can just avoid doing some things while on public wifi.
A VPN though, that could make things much easier!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Ramblings of a Frustrated Cybernerd</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2015/08/saturday-ramblings-of-a-frustrated-cybernerd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 19:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2015/08/saturday-ramblings-of-a-frustrated-cybernerd/</guid>
      <description>This is one of those Saturdays where I&amp;rsquo;m finding it hard to focus on what I want to focus on. Ok, so that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty regular problem for me on Saturday. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to focus on programming for this volunteer activity I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be leading in September. I&amp;rsquo;ve got to build some software for the event, and make some decisions, and wrap it all up at some point. It&amp;rsquo;s not too far from being done, and I guess this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve had to just sit and think a bit this week, so maybe that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m not too concerned about being unproductive, and I&amp;rsquo;m just letting my mind wander.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the Van Allen Belts</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2014/03/engineering-the-van-allen-belts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 19:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2014/03/engineering-the-van-allen-belts/</guid>
      <description>This article proposes a pretty crazy sounding idea - remove the Van Allen Belts.
Simplified Explanatory Summary: The Van Allen Belts are a natural phenomenon, electrons and protons flying around the Earth at high speed. Electrical current is essentially electrons moving around, so when astronauts or satellites pass through these regions the effect is shocking. Passing through the proton regions is even worse because they&amp;rsquo;re comparatively mass-ive. Electrons and protons are normally flying around in space, but these ones are trapped by Earth&amp;rsquo;s magnetic field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Economist on US Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/06/the-economist-on-us-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 20:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/06/the-economist-on-us-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>This article in The Economist summarizes most of the issues relevant to this whole Edward Snowden debacle. Their attitude is that the amount of secret surveillance going on in the US, as suggested by the current news cycle, makes democracy difficult. It&amp;rsquo;s worth a skim just to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re not missing some chunk of the debate and recent history. The Economist is about as much a disinterested third party as I can think of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plunger</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/02/plunger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 02:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/02/plunger/</guid>
      <description>A wooden stick with a rubber cone on the end can solve so many problems.
 When the toilet&amp;rsquo;s on the fritz, But you&amp;rsquo;ve really got the shitz, You&amp;rsquo;ve got to plunge it. You&amp;rsquo;ve got to plunge it.
  That cat clogged the toilet. PLUNGE HIM.
   When your dinner&amp;rsquo;s in the pot, But your sink has got a clot, You&amp;rsquo;ve got to plunge it. You&amp;rsquo;ve got to plunge it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Antonio Hackerspace</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/02/san-antonio-hackerspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 20:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/02/san-antonio-hackerspace/</guid>
      <description>Apparently San Antonio has a hackerspace now. Up until a few minutes ago, this image was alongside the rest of their &amp;ldquo;About Us&amp;rdquo; page. I think that by observing the page I changed it, so perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s a quantum webpage.
 Leia&amp;rsquo;s going to cut her tongue if she&amp;rsquo;s not careful.
  Anyway, these are a bunch of nerds interested in ham radio, building hardware and software, and talking about all these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unix Text Editing Awesomeness</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/02/unix-awesomeness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 17:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/02/unix-awesomeness/</guid>
      <description>Oh, LaTeX acronym package, you won&amp;rsquo;t automatically alphabetize my list of acronyms? Strange&amp;hellip; Let&amp;rsquo;s see if Unix will&amp;hellip;
$ echo &amp;quot;\acro{SCADA}{Supervisory Control And Data Acquisition} \acro{PLC}{Programmable Logic Controller} \acro{RTU}{Remote Terminal Unit} ...&amp;quot; &amp;gt; toSort $ for i in `cat toSort |sed &amp;quot;s/.*\\acro{\(.*\)}.*{.*}/\1/&amp;quot; | sort`; do grep &amp;quot;{$i}&amp;quot; toSort; done \acro{ADC}{analog to digital converter} \acro{API}{application programming interface} \acro{APT}{Advanced Persistent Threat} \acro{ASCII}{American Standard Code for Information Interchange} ... Unix, you rock my world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Have An Awesome Weekend Anywhere in the Country</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/01/how-to-have-an-awesome-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/01/how-to-have-an-awesome-weekend/</guid>
      <description>Somebody gave this post on BuzzFeed the title, &amp;ldquo;How to Date Anywhere in the Country,&amp;rdquo; but really it should be called, &amp;ldquo;How to Have an Awesome Weekend in the Biggest Cities in the Country&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s not as catchy I guess. For San Antonio it mentions the Flying Saucer, Ranger Creek Brewery, the Japanese Tea Gardens, and Candlelight Coffee. Chicago - Millenium Park and the Art Museum. Cleveland - Great Lakes Brewery&amp;hellip; Austin - Zilker Park, the Drafthouse&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More to Life than Being Happy</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/01/more-to-life-than-being-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 20:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/01/more-to-life-than-being-happy/</guid>
      <description>This article in the Atlantic struck a chord with me. It&amp;rsquo;s about how, in life, searching for meaning can leave people more satisfied than searching for happiness.
 As [Viktor Frankl] saw in the [concentration] camps, those who found meaning even in the most horrendous circumstances were far more resilient to suffering than those who did not. &amp;ldquo;Everything can be taken from a man but one thing&amp;rdquo;.
 Meaning, more than happiness, is long-term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Compro-Flirt</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/01/the-compro-flirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 03:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2013/01/the-compro-flirt/</guid>
      <description>Some times I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether I&amp;rsquo;m trying to flirt with someone or not. The coffee shop was playing some crazy music from all over the World, like, a French song followed by some crazy Spanish dudes shouting to a dance tune.
&amp;ldquo;Heh, this music&amp;hellip; right?&amp;rdquo; Surely anybody would agree this was a crazy mix.
&amp;ldquo;I kinda like it&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; she said.
&amp;ldquo;Yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s alright&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; This reply doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any thought. I put my foot in my mouth so often, this reply is just a reflex at this point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Dictionary - Terrible Hack of the Day</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/12/bash-dictionary-terrible-hack-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 21:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/12/bash-dictionary-terrible-hack-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>So, I just had a reason to implement something like a dictionary in Bash. Of course, I could try to determine if such a feature exists already (it does in Bash 4, alas the default on OS X seems to be 3.2), but why not just try to hack something together?
Here&amp;rsquo;s what I got initially:
OFFSETDICTkeyUno=5 OFFSETDICTkeyDos=4 OFFSETDICTkeyTres=17 OFFSETDICTkeyQuatro=21 keyToLookup=&amp;quot;keyQuatro&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;$(eval echo &#39;$OFFSETDICT&#39;${keyToLookup})&amp;quot; echo $value &amp;gt; 21 So, that&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteor Shower</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/12/meteor-shower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 16:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/12/meteor-shower/</guid>
      <description>The back of a truck is an appropriate place to watch a meteor shower. I had driven out onto a back road in Yellow Springs, Ohio, to watch the meteors fall, and I was not disappointed. Orion knew where most of them were coming from - he was calling the shots.
I had barely pulled off the two-lane dirt road and onto some tire tracks in the grass. A run-down barbed wire fence with old knotty posts ran alongside the road, and was only a few feet from the truck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Wonderful...</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/11/its-wonderful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 02:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/11/its-wonderful/</guid>
      <description>I dream of you, chips chips chips, du du du du du
 It was just a song, but one that Starbucks seemed to have on a tight loop. Every time I&amp;rsquo;d walk into one of the four Starbucks I had on rotation I&amp;rsquo;d hear the song - I&amp;rsquo;d hear it twenty times.
The first few times I heard that old crooner belting out the difficult-to-understand lyrics, I enjoyed myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Port</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/11/open-port/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2012 15:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/11/open-port/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then when I&amp;rsquo;m at a coffee shop I wonder what ports I&amp;rsquo;ve got open on my home network. Normally I don&amp;rsquo;t have any ports open within Nmap&amp;rsquo;s default port list.
Starting Nmap 6.01 Initiating SYN Stealth Scan at 16:41 Scanning myRouter [1000 ports] Discovered open port 1111/tcp on myRouter Completed SYN Stealth Scan (1000 total ports) Not shown: 999 filtered ports PORT STATE SERVICE 1111/tcp open lmsocialserver Read data files from: /usr/local/bin/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mustache November</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/11/mustache-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 01:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/11/mustache-november/</guid>
      <description>For some reason November is now Mustache November. Now we&amp;rsquo;ve got two months out of the year where we have to grow mustaches? I don&amp;rsquo;t get it. This is supposed to be some statement about masculinity or something? Whatever. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to grow a mustache, ride a motorcycle, or drink whiskey, to be a man (although admittedly all those things are awesome).
Men should know how to stop a toilet that&amp;rsquo;s overflowing, and we should know how to change a tire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Scholar Does Citations</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/10/google-scholar-does-citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 19:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/10/google-scholar-does-citations/</guid>
      <description>Google Scholar just added a citations feature which, among other things, lets you get a BibTeX formatted citation. This is so handy, and I&amp;rsquo;ve wondered for a while why they didn&amp;rsquo;t have that feature in there. Often you can go to the IEEE page or whatever to get the citation, but some journals make you login (IEEE, why do you do that?) and anyway this makes one less click.
  To copy a formatted citation, click on the “Cite” link below a search result and select from the available citation styles (currently MLA, APA, or Chicago) [&amp;hellip;] You can also use one of the import links to import the citation into BibTeX or another bibliography manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python&#39;s super()</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/10/pythons-super/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 14:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/10/pythons-super/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing a lot of Python lately, and there are some things I love about it, some things I&amp;rsquo;m uncomfortable with, but nothing I hate. The super() builtin function makes life a lot easier when you&amp;rsquo;re using Python for object oriented code and have some inheritance going on. This blog post describes the best way I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it used so far.
First of all, in Python3 you no longer need to write &amp;ldquo;super(CurrentClass, self).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Bond Infographic</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/10/james-bond-infographic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 19:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/10/james-bond-infographic/</guid>
      <description>So, you can spend all kinds of time looking through IMDB trying to get the order of the bond movies correct, or you can just look at this great infographic, thanks to these guys.

So helpful, right? They put the years right there on the left side (it&amp;rsquo;d be easy not to notice that).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Graphics Stack - Meta</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/10/the-linux-graphics-stack-meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 15:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/10/the-linux-graphics-stack-meta/</guid>
      <description>Jasper St. Pierre explains the Linux graphics stack in detail.
I think X11 is the most complex piece of software I&amp;rsquo;ve ever tried to work with. It has been a long time since I&amp;rsquo;ve had to open up xorg.conf (and before that I think it was x11.conf) to fix something that&amp;rsquo;s broken, and that&amp;rsquo;s a testament to the quality of modern versions of Ubuntu and Debian. But there was a day when I had to open that massive config file up quite often to get the video card, or mouse, or keyboard or whatever working properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screen Scrollback Buffer</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/08/screen-scrollback-buffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 17:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/08/screen-scrollback-buffer/</guid>
      <description>I end up using GNU &amp;ldquo;screen&amp;rdquo; a lot. It lets me SSH into my laptop, run something, then close the SSH connection with the task still running in the background. Later I can SSH in and regain control of the task. It&amp;rsquo;s helpful for Counter-Strike server admin, compiling stuff, or building a test corpus&amp;hellip;
Anyway, screen interferes with the regular terminal&amp;rsquo;s ability to scroll back and view previous program output. Today I found a description of how to fix that problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apocalypse Not</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/08/apocalypse-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 22:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/08/apocalypse-not/</guid>
      <description>Wired has a great article up right now.
 When the sun rises on December 22, as it surely will, do not expect apologies or even a rethink. No matter how often apocalyptic predictions fail to come true, another one soon arrives.
 They chronicle some of the apocalyptic predictions of the past 50 years or so, including acid rain, CFCs, famine, and oil shortage. I think the folks who make these predictions often want to focus humanity&amp;rsquo;s attention on some important issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orwell Quote</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/08/orwell-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 05:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/08/orwell-quote/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading Animal Farm and found a great quote attributed to Orwell by Wikipedia.
 The sinister fact about literary censorship in England is that it is largely voluntary. &amp;hellip; Things are kept right out of the British press, not because the Government intervenes but because of a general tacit agreement that &amp;lsquo;it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do&amp;rsquo; to mention that particular fact.
 He was speaking sometime around World War II.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook is not AFF</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/facebook-is-not-aff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 03:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/facebook-is-not-aff/</guid>
      <description>So, maybe a year ago I changed my &amp;ldquo;religion&amp;rdquo; on Facebook, because I wanted to make sure I had something in there that really defined me. I settled on &amp;ldquo;Coed Naked Motorcycle Hiking&amp;rdquo;, because I like motorcycles and I like hiking and &amp;ldquo;coed naked&amp;rdquo; seems to go pretty well in front of anything. Facebook didn&amp;rsquo;t think this religion existed, so I created a page complete with a photo from Waking Ned Devine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Trek Had it Right </title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/star-trek-had-it-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 04:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/star-trek-had-it-right/</guid>
      <description>Star Trek had it right. They were a bunch of peace loving (except for Worf) scientists roaming the universe in a war ship. They always kept their cool when someone faced them down, but if they needed to Jean Luc had no problem blasting the enemy out of the sky.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Animal Farm recently, and it has impressed upon me the need to maintain arms and a force capable of using them no matter how peaceful society gets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 23:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/reading-list/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of great papers in Computer Science. There are some great papers on there, but one thing missing is the book, Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs. That&amp;rsquo;s not exactly a paper, I suppose, but it is one of the most influential programming books.
Regarding books that I need to read, here&amp;rsquo;s a list of 88 books that influenced America. I need to remember to read some of those, along with The Old Man and the Sea&amp;hellip; I guess I just need to finish that last one at some point&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starbucks Mugs</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/starbucksmugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 18:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/starbucksmugs/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Here&amp;rsquo;s your coffee. I gave it to you in a large mug because I think I broke all the medium ones.&amp;rdquo;
Laughing, &amp;ldquo;what?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Yeah, well, we moved all the glasses down low, and whenever I open the cabinet one falls out.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surveillance Art</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/surveillance-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 01:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/surveillance-art/</guid>
      <description>Wired has some great reporting, and this story is no different.
 On July 3rd, I installed this exhibition app on all the free computers at the 14th Street Apple Store. [&amp;hellip;] When the slideshow first opened, it would capture an image of whoever was standing in front of the computer, and show them first before fading into the previously captured photos.
 It&amp;rsquo;s the backstory behind the &amp;ldquo;People Staring at Computers&amp;rdquo; art exhibit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peppers and Coffee for the Heat</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/peppersandcoffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 15:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/peppersandcoffee/</guid>
      <description>This article from NPR will be interesting to any chili pepper fans, and to anybody who has enjoyed drinking coffee on a hot day.
 &amp;ldquo;The hot drink somehow has an effect on your systemic cooling mechanisms, which exceeds its actual effect in terms of heating your body,&amp;rdquo; says McNaughton.
 It&amp;rsquo;s a look at why Indians drink hot tea, because you know, it&amp;rsquo;s hot there. Why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t they drink cold water or a soda?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middle Eastern Language Patterns</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/middle-eastern-language-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 03:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/middle-eastern-language-patterns/</guid>
      <description>I dropped cable TV a few years ago, and when I finally got a Roku I started getting some news again. Watching the Arab Spring on CNN International last year, and tuning into Al Jazeera English at any time, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that interviewees from the Middle East tend to use many more analogies than Western speakers. These news channels interviewed folks from all walks of life all over North Africa, and out to Afghanistan, and I noticed this pattern regularly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP: The Right Way</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/php-the-right-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 20:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/07/php-the-right-way/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of pitfalls to using PHP, and they bite new users quickly. &amp;ldquo;Spot the vulnerability&amp;rdquo; is a cool site which highlights examples of these pitfalls: http://spotthevuln.com/ (BROKEN NOW)
Of course, PHP is a pretty speedy way to develop any type of server-side web code. Josh Lockhart has put together a list of best practices for PHP development and tailored it to new PHP developers: http://www.phptherightway.com/
If developers would follow the recommendations in the databases section it would take care of so many vulnerabilities out there today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify Your Writing</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/01/simplify-your-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 21:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/01/simplify-your-writing/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5 in Godel, Escher, Bach, section Recursion in Language, has a great example of how my writing needed to be simplified for technical writing. It describes how asides in writing, created by commas and parentheticals, are similar to pushing and popping the writing&amp;rsquo;s context to a stack. There is always a way to simplify that writing, it suggests.
Pretty smart&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced SQL Injection</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/07/advanced-sql-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/07/advanced-sql-injection/</guid>
      <description>Ok, here&amp;rsquo;s a great blog post by Chris Shiflett about a crazy-creative SQL injection technique: http://shiflett.org/blog/2006/jan/addslashes-versus-mysql-real-escape-string
Very cool. His technique relies on tricking addslashes into breaking up a two byte character with a slash, creating a valid two byte character followed by a valid one byte character. He mentions that this (specific attack) is impossible with UTF-8 because all two (or more) byte characters have continuation bytes that start with 0b10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Yoda&#34; Conditions</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/04/yoda-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/04/yoda-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a creative idea I&amp;rsquo;d never considered before. I&amp;rsquo;ve written code like this, but accidentally, and then it looks wrong so I change it back. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick example:
if ( 42 == myInt ) as opposed to if ( myInt == 42 )
The former may be better to use because occasionally we all forget to put that second &amp;ldquo;=&amp;rdquo; in there, and we accidentally turn our comparison operator into an assignment operator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LCD Modules</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/04/lcd-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 15:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/04/lcd-modules/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never built anything with an LCD on it before, but it seems like it&amp;rsquo;d be useful. Here&amp;rsquo;s some good info on creating an project with an LCD and an Arduino:
http://arduino.cc/en/Reference/LiquidCrystal
It&amp;rsquo;s a library of functions that make it very easy to work with the LCD controller. The controller has to be compatible with the HD44780 controller&amp;rsquo;s instruction set, but that&amp;rsquo;s basically an industry standard. Mouser has a selection of 20x4 character displays:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS / Div Tag Webpage Layout</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/03/css-div-tag-webpage-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 14:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/03/css-div-tag-webpage-layout/</guid>
      <description>http://960.gs/
960 Grid System seems like a great, easy way to setup the layout of a webpage using modern HTML and CSS techniques. Very cool.
http://www.blueprintcss.org/
Blueprint CSS is also something to check out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MinGW and Cygwin to build a Windows DLL</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/03/mingw-and-cygwin-to-build-a-windows-dll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 19:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/03/mingw-and-cygwin-to-build-a-windows-dll/</guid>
      <description>I was writing C++ in Linux - gvim + aterm is my development environment of choice. I needed to turn my code into a Windows DLL, though, and the following webpage was really helpful.
http://www.mingw.org/wiki/sampleDLL
I installed Cygwin in a Windows XP virtual machine, used Cygwin to install MinGW, modded my code and Makefile a bit based on the samples on that page, then ran &amp;ldquo;make windows&amp;rdquo; in that virtual machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; FAQ</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/02/c-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/02/c-faq/</guid>
      <description>Marshall Cline&amp;rsquo;s C++ FAQ is great - very comprehensive. It covers topics useful to everyone from beginners to intermediate/advanced users. It&amp;rsquo;s at:
http://www.parashift.com/c++-faq-lite/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hooking Netfilter with a Linux Kernel Module</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/02/hooking-netfilter-with-a-linux-kernel-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 04:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2011/02/hooking-netfilter-with-a-linux-kernel-module/</guid>
      <description>http://www.linuxjournal.com/article/7184
This is a great Linux Journal article where they write a kernel module to hook Netfilter. It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be useful to me at some point.
What other things in the kernel can be hooked? I&amp;rsquo;m sure the list is freakin long, but this would be fun to experiment with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comp Sec Sites</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2009/08/comp-sec-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 18:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2009/08/comp-sec-sites/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m gonna use this to record interesting/useful information on computer security. Starting off with a post on switch hardening - these are complex switches we&amp;rsquo;re talking about:
http://isc.sans.org/diary.html?storyid=6910&amp;amp;rss;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geotagging Photos</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2009/05/geotagging-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 20:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2009/05/geotagging-photos/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m disappointed by the way Picasa handles geotagging photos in Linux. It looks like the newest version doesn&amp;rsquo;t support geotagging. Not only that, but when it resizes images to upload to Picasa on the web, it kills any EXIF information that may have specified a location. What the heck Picasa? Why you gotta clobber my shit?
I can preserve the geotags by uploading directly from my G1 (slow), or by going to the Picasa website and uploading from there (can&amp;rsquo;t do a batch upload, also can&amp;rsquo;t resize automatically).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Chili Recipe</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2009/04/current-chili-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2009 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2009/04/current-chili-recipe/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s my current chili recipe. This one is going to be awesome when it&amp;rsquo;s all done. It&amp;rsquo;s good enough right now that I have a hard time sticking to my plan to make it awesome without the spiciness, then add the spicy in later. The last few times I&amp;rsquo;ve made it I&amp;rsquo;ve added in the peppers&amp;hellip; Shame on me. It&amp;rsquo;s just too tasty to resist.
1 can bush kidney beans 1/2 can bush pinto beans 1 lb browned ground beef 1 can hunts diced tomatoes 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movies To See</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2009/03/movies-to-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2009/03/movies-to-see/</guid>
      <description>Here are a few movies I need to see: Brazil The Adventures of Buckaroo Banzai Across the 8th Dimension There Will Be Blood Empire of the Sun Ghost in the Machine The Warriors Lost Boys
 Comments:  Karl - Apr 2, 2009
Beyond the Valley of the Dolls
Also, get a copy of the old Casino Royale&amp;hellip;
  Karl - May 1, 2009
Also see Public Enemy and Little Caesar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chiltepin Batch 1 Day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2009/02/chiltepin-batch-1-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 23:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2009/02/chiltepin-batch-1-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I planted 10 of my Chiltepin seeds today. At Lowes, I picked up some seedling mix, a 11.5&amp;rdquo; clay dish and a 10&amp;rdquo; plastic dish insert.
These are chili peppers that are used to dry climates, and several websites I&amp;rsquo;ve seen suggest the seeds should not be watered too much. To avoid problems with overwatering, I poked holes in the bottom of the plastic dish, filled the clay dish with sand, then put the plastic dish containing the soil on top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WWI</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2008/01/wwi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2008 07:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2008/01/wwi/</guid>
      <description>Grenade in Foxhole
Hopeful glance at other man
Bend to throw, heads bump!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Service Announcement</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2008/01/public-service-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2008 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2008/01/public-service-announcement/</guid>
      <description>PSA: Don&amp;rsquo;t follow Starbucks&amp;rsquo; directions for making coffee if you like it black.
Backstory: I usually make four cups of coffee whenever I need some. I&amp;rsquo;m feeling particularly lazy (it&amp;rsquo;s a Saturday and I got excused from going into the office to get shot at) and I&amp;rsquo;d like to get some exercise, so I put a pot on. That&amp;rsquo;s four cups based on the coffee pot markings. Starbucks&amp;rsquo; directions say use 2 Tbsp (10 grams) per 6 fl oz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ahhnold</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2008/01/ahhnold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2008 02:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2008/01/ahhnold/</guid>
      <description>Why does Arnold Schwarzenegger rock so much? I&amp;rsquo;m sitting on the couch, watching True Lies and Jamie Lee Curtis is trying to screw around with another man. Why? Because she doesn&amp;rsquo;t know the true Arnold. For those who haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the movie, Schwarzenwhatever is a spy for the US. Come on, ladies love that kinda stuff, right? Anyway, what is Curtis thinking?
Then there&amp;rsquo;s his other movie. Commando. What is the most awesome part of Commando?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Story Ideas (a.k.a. First Post)</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2008/01/cool-story-ideas-a-k-a-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 07:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2008/01/cool-story-ideas-a-k-a-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so tonight, lying in bed, I had a few cool story ideas. If someone steals these to make a book, well, congratulations, your mind is as insane as mine. Plus, you have to send me one free review copy. That&amp;rsquo;s all I ask.
 The important part here is that an entire story line gets planned out (the story line doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter right now) and it&amp;rsquo;s a five book series.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>