<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cooking on Karl&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.notmet.net/categories/cooking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cooking on Karl&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 15:30:18 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.notmet.net/categories/cooking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grilling a Whole Chicken Texas</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/06/grilling-a-whole-chicken-texas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 15:30:18 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/06/grilling-a-whole-chicken-texas/</guid>
      <description>Time to grill a chicken! We&amp;rsquo;re using mojo sauce from HEB - it&amp;rsquo;s oil, Mediterranean flavors, a bit of citrus and spice. I got a &amp;ldquo;roaster&amp;rdquo;-sized chicken, and want the temperature to hit 165℉.
1930: butterflied chicken is on the cool side of a two zone grill, skin up and legs toward the hot. Burner is on half, initial grill temperature says 350℉.
1955: chicken hadn&amp;rsquo;t hit 100℉ yet, and the grill was still at 350℉ so I turned it up to about 3/4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lambtastic</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/04/lambtastic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 11:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/04/lambtastic/</guid>
      <description>This is lamb weekend. Some folks call it Easter weekend. I&amp;rsquo;m doing two legs of lamb - right leg and left leg. Both are about 4.7 lbs, $5.99 per pound. Today, Saturday, I&amp;rsquo;m going to smoke one based on this recipe, and tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m going to Sous Vide one based on the same recipe I&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past. Sarah likes meat more well-done than I do, and with lamb I don&amp;rsquo;t mind that much, so my target is medium-well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grilling a Whole Chicken</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/grilling-a-whole-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2019/03/grilling-a-whole-chicken/</guid>
      <description>We have a leftover chicken in the freezer, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to grill up a whole chicken again! We thawed it in the fridge over a couple days, then I marinated it in a bottle of Jerk sauce. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t found a great bottle of Jerk sauce - none are even approaching the right spiciness. Oh well. The chicken is medium sized, not as large as a roaster.
1910: Started butterflied chicken on the grill, cold side, skin up, legs towards the fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBQ Chicken</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/05/bbq-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 17:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/05/bbq-chicken/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been grilling for a while. Years. Have I ever taken it seriously? Yes - well, seriously enough to find that steak recipe I like&amp;hellip; Seriously enough to find that grilled whole chicken recipe I like&amp;hellip; Seriously enough to switch to a charcoal chimney&amp;hellip; All-in-all, maybe more serious than the casual griller, but not much more serious than that.
This memorial day, it&amp;rsquo;s time to BBQ a whole chicken. I mean - grill a chicken and use BBQ sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sous Vide Lamb Leg</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/sous-vide-lamb-leg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 19:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/sous-vide-lamb-leg/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a couple cooking projects going on today. I&amp;rsquo;m planning to be home all day, so I&amp;rsquo;ve started up a lamb leg in the Sous Vide. It&amp;rsquo;s a 5 lbs New Zealand lamb leg from Costco, all tied up.
 1 Tbsp salt 2 Tbsp melted butter 1 Tbsp (actually, a bit more) fresh rosemary 1 tsp pepper (or so) 6 big cloves of garlic 14 Kalmata olives  I put all that in the food processor and went until the garlic and rosemary were minced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sous Vide Burgers</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/sous-vide-burgers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 23:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2018/02/sous-vide-burgers/</guid>
      <description>* 1.5 Tbsp Worcester sauce per pound of meat * 2 Tbsp Duke&#39;s Mayo per pound of meat * .5 Tbsp minded garlic per pound of meat * 85% Ground Beef  Tonight we&amp;rsquo;re trying this recipe, and I made 8 7.5 oz burgers, starting from almost 3.5 lbs beef. I dropped all but two bagged burgers into the deep freeze, and dropped the other two in the indoors freezer, and then sous-vide&amp;rsquo;d those two at 130° for 1 hour, so they should come out on the rare side of medium.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
