<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Karl&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.notmet.net/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Karl&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.notmet.net/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scope: Not Just Mouthwash</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/scope-not-just-mouthwash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/02/scope-not-just-mouthwash/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m teaching a Python class which acts as an introduction to programming, for most of the students there. This is an awesome experience - for me personally because I enjoy this, and for my resume. I hope to do this full-time someday, but today I&amp;rsquo;ve just got 3 sections of the same class.
We&amp;rsquo;re doing a lot of cool things that I should write about some other time - one of them is using a free, open source textbook called, Runestone - How to Think Like a Computer Scientist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax Errors</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/syntax-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:15:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2020/01/syntax-errors/</guid>
      <description>Syntax Errors in Python are great. Here&amp;rsquo;s one:
 File &amp;quot;asdf.py&amp;quot;, line 2 print(&amp;quot;Result is: {}&amp;quot;.format(result)) ^ SyntaxError: invalid syntax result = ((5 * 10) + 15 print(&amp;#34;Result is: {}&amp;#34;.format(result)) Two lines of code&amp;hellip; Syntax error on the print line, evidently. But where? That line looks so simple and correct! And pointing directly at the t?
Well - it&amp;rsquo;s not really on the print line. Folks who have done any amount of programming will look at the preceeding line fairly quickly and notice the missing parenthesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RasPi Flow Meter In A Pinch - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2016/08/raspi-flow-meter-in-a-pinch-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2016/08/raspi-flow-meter-in-a-pinch-part-2/</guid>
      <description>META: Part 1 describes the problem I&amp;rsquo;m trying to solve here.
I need a way to monitor water flow through my water filter over several days, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to sit and watch it.
So - I took a Raspberry Pi I&amp;rsquo;ve got and a little Python and hacked a solution together. The basic idea was that I&amp;rsquo;d position a plastic cup below the output stream of the waste water, I&amp;rsquo;d put two wires into the cup, I&amp;rsquo;d put a voltage on one wire and attempt to see the voltage on the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python&#39;s super()</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/10/pythons-super/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 14:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kc0bfv@notmet.net (Karl Sickendick)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.notmet.net/2012/10/pythons-super/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing a lot of Python lately, and there are some things I love about it, some things I&amp;rsquo;m uncomfortable with, but nothing I hate. The super() builtin function makes life a lot easier when you&amp;rsquo;re using Python for object oriented code and have some inheritance going on. This blog post describes the best way I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it used so far.
First of all, in Python3 you no longer need to write &amp;ldquo;super(CurrentClass, self).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>